Pedro Azevedo Minutentag

SP, São Paulo | +55 (11) 97659-3112 pedro.azvm@gmail.com

Summary

I am a hands-on software architect who enjoys both designing and developing complex applications.

Knowledgeable on the entire software development cycle, including planning, design, implementation and testing.

Worked on multiple types of projects: on-premise, cloud and migration projects.

Lead teams on an Agile environment utilizing enterprise tools such as Jira, Github, SwaggerHub.

Have experience on a range of technologies, developing C# / Javascript / Java / C++ / React and Angular applications. Also designed and provisioned applications targeting Azure, AWS and GCP.

Links

Github: https://github.com/pedroaz

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedro-azevedo-627ab8b2/

Personal project: https://atmos-cloud.com/

Skills

C#, JavaScript, Cloud Computing, Python, React, Angular, Java, Software Development Life Cycle, Web Development, C++, Node.js, Git, AWS, Azure, GCP, Agile, Docker

Experience

RDI - Capgemini (McDonalds account)

Software Architect | 04/2019 - Present

Started at RDI as a software developer working on the Market Adoption team. Worked for a year solving multiple production issues on an environment which has over 14.000 restaurants. Supported system which were built using C++/C#/J ava and Javascript.

Was transferred to the architecture team of the company to design and work on a new cloud application for automated deployments. Assumed more responsibilities on the design part and interacting with the client. Developed a microservices system on azure using C# and Angular.

Later I was moved to a Transformation project where I was assigned a lead role to work with over 36 squads. Working on both the application design (C# microservices and Angular microfrontends) and non-functional components (Ansible, Docker, Traefik, NATS, automation tools).

Besides my technical participation, also daily interact with product owners, stakeholders and other architects to help align prioritizations and technical concerns. Went as far as travel to the client to help on the deployments and product negociations.

Jive Investments

Jr. Software Developer | 01/2019 - 04/2019

Worked in an asset management firm, creating data mining process with Python and managing a SQL Server database.

Introduced software development processes and helped design a cloud based architecture on AWS.

Bridge Games

Game Developer | 07/2018 - 12/2018

Worked in a startup developing games using Unity3D engine and C# / Javascript.

Worked close to the users and wrote several C# tools to help the project developement.

Self Employed

08/2017 - 12/2017

Started a small company developing VR applications for architectural projects.

Developed Unity3D applications / AWS integrations.

B3

Internship | 01/2016 - 07/2017

Worked in the department of credit analysis alongside statisticians and economists developing software for data analysis.

Developed systems using R and Python and created web widgets using Shiny.

Education

USP

MBA Project Management | 01/2024

TISP

Information System | 12/2018

USP

Physics

(Interrupted after 3 years)

Languages

English, Portuguese